Finding Aid for the Edwin Mims Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- N.D.'S
  - "Professor Gilbert Murray, Seventieth Birthday Honoured," The Times, London. (Box 18)
  - "Southern Literature," by W.M. Baskerville. (Box 18)
  - "The Two Conservatisms," by Clinton Rossiter. (Box 18)
  - "What Is ‘The Last Death'?," by Ralph McGill. (Box 18)
  - Also 6 titled fragments, and misc. untitled fragments not indexed. (Box 18)
  - Comments - by others about Mims' lecture tours (Phi Beta Kappa, Carnegie, etc.) (Box 19)
  - French Diary (Box 19)
  - Lecture Programs, Course Syllabus (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Anti-Lynching Movement" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Anti-Lynching Petition" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Atticus G. Haygood: Liberal Spokesman of the New South" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - Autobiographical fragment - education in the South, etc. (Box 19)
  - Mss. - Autogiographical fragment - regions of U.S. (Box 19)
  - Mss. - Autobiographical fragment - South Atlantic Quarterly (Box 19)
  - Mss. - Book Reviews (Box 19)
  - Mss. -"Booker Washington in Boston" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Bright Eyes" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Chancellor Kirkland and Vanderbilt University" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Ellen Glasgow: Social Historian of Virginia" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "French Literary Influence on England and U.S. (incomplete) (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "A Group of Southern Historians" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Henry Grady" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "In Search of the United States" + Review (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "A Man and a Book" (Atticus G. Haygood) (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "The Mid-Victorians" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - Milton (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Mr. Menoken and Mr. Sherman..." (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Modern Education and Religion" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "New Light on an Old Problem" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Obligations of American Life", "Options", "Peace and World Order", "Thomas Nelson Page - A Reminiscence" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "Personal Experiences with Southern Authors" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - (Professor Gildersleeve) (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "A Reconsideration of Early Southern Literature" (Box 19)
  - Mss. - "The Romance and Realism of the West" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "Samuel Johnson" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "A Semi-Centennial Survey of North Carolina's Intellectual Progress" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "Sidney Lanier and Higher Education" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "Sixty Years in the Classroom" (Box 20)
  - Mss.- "The South Realizing Itself" ("Hartsville and Its Lesson") (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "Southern Conference for Education in the South" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - (Southern "Profiles in Courage") (incomplete) (Box 20)
  - Mss. -"Southern Rebels of Another Type" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "A Tramp Trip through the Smoky Mountains" (Box 20)
  - Mss. - "The Voice of the Negro" (Box 20)
  - Misc. Lists and Programs (C.S. Johnson Funeral) (Box 20)
  - Misc. Ms. Material - typed original (autobiographical) (Box 20)
  - Misc. Ms. Material - typed carbons (autobiographical) (Box 20)
  - Misc. Ms. Material typed originals (general) (4 folders) (Box 20)
  - Misc. Ms. Material - typed carbons (general) (Box 20)
  - Misc. Notes, Mss. etc. (9 folders) (Box 21)
  - Notes on Peace (Box 21)
  - Notes on Rev. J. Galluchat (Box 21)
  - Pamphlets - by others (Box 21)
  - Passport, Photograph (latter of Hiram Lorson?) (Box 21)
  - Publisher's Mtls. - Misc. (Box 22)
  - Research Notes (8 folders) (Box 22)
  - Scottish Diary (Box 22)
  - "The Southern Woman - Past and Present" (Essay by Mims in Bulletin of Randolph-Macon Woman's College, Lynchburg, Va.) (Box 22)
  - Travel Accounts (Box 22)
  - Tributes and Biographical Mtl. (Box 22)